# 大家好 現在天氣越來越冷啦
Hi everyone! It's getting really cold now.
# 家裡的小狗 那個窩哇
Our puppies, their kennel...
# 你看
Look!
# 到處都 晚上到處都睡覺
Everywhere, they sleep everywhere at night.
# 沒有固定的窩
Ah! They're don't have a fixed kennel.
# 我給它做一個小 做一個窩
I'll make them a small, make them a kennel,
# 做一個比較暖和的窩
make them a warmer kennel.
# 小狗 走開走開走開
Puppies! Go 'way, go 'way!
# 這個毯子還是我以前睡過的
It's a blanket that I've used before.
# 全部給 給它啦
I'll give, give them all.
# 睡了七八年啦
I've used it for like seven or eight years.
# 嗯 還可以睡的哦
Um! It's still in a rather good condition.
# 你看 這個毯子
Look! The blanket,
# 那麼大 貼在這裡就好啦
it's so large. I can just leave it right here.
# 很睡和的哦 這裡哦
It's really warm here.
# 小狗
Puppies!
# 狗 狗狗狗狗狗 過來
Puppies! Puppies, puppies, puppies, come here!
# 大狗你們 你們不用 不用窩的你們 那麼大了
Big dogs, you, you don't need, you don't need a kennel. You're that big now.
# 額 在這裡睡覺
Eh! Sleep here!
# 在這裡睡覺
Sleep here!
# 這裡睡覺很舒服的
Sleeping here is really comfortable.
# 又沒有風
The wind is blocked.
# 多好哇
Isn't it good?
# 你看 它們很喜歡這個窩哦
Look! They like the kennel so much.
# 來 你也進去
C'mon! Go to the kennel!
# 趴在這睡覺
Lie down here and sleep!
# 全部在這裡睡覺
Everybody sleep here!
# 額 吃飽了撐著沒事做就要幹架
Eh! When they've stuffed their stomach, they just fight if they have nothing better to do.
# 你看 是不是 很喜歡這個窩哦
Look! Right? You like the kennel so much.
# 你看 就這樣
Look! So, then,
# 7隻小狗就睡在這裡 今天晚上
all seven puppies will be sleeping here, tonight.
# 應該來說是可以呀 跟我來
There shouldn't be any problems. Come with me!
# 來來來來來來 可以可以可以
Come, come, come, come, come! O~kay, okay, okay!
# 不要打架啊
Don't fight!
# 那麼兇幹嘛
Why are you so fierce?
# 你看 這個窩就做好啦
Look! The kennel is done.
# 這條小狗 小狗小狗小狗
This puppy, puppy, puppy, puppy!
# 它好乖喲 這小狗
It's so nice, this puppy.
# 嘿喲 你打我 你咬我幹嘛
Heyo! Why did you beat me, why did you bite me?
# 你看 它那麼不聽話
Look! It's so naughty.
# 它想咬我
It wants to bite me.
# 竟然咬我
It bites me.
# 敢不敢啦
Do you still dare?
Do you?
# 來呀 敢不敢啦
C'mon! You dare to bite me?
# 你咬不到我了哇
You just can't bite me.
# 太壞啦
Naughty!
# 今天晚上你們就睡在這裡啊
Sleep here tonight! Got it?
# 別那麼兇 誰 誰在叫的
Don't be so fierce. Who, who's groaning?
# 不許叫啊
No groaning!
# 就你是不是
Isn't it you?
# 你看 看著這個
Look! Look at this one!
# 被那個大狗 跟了一下它的鼻子
It was kicked on the nose, by a big dog.
# 毛都掉啦
The hair came off here.
# 看你還敢不敢
See if you still dare.
# 那麼小 那麼小都去
You're that tiny, that tiny, but you still,
# 惹那個大狗
dare to provoke the big dogs.
# 敢不敢啦
Do you still dare?
# 你看 嘴巴 牙齒都長出來啦
Look! The mouth, the teeth are already coming out.
# 很能吃的哦 它們哦
They're great eaters, all of them,
# 吃了好胖的
and are so fat now.
# 吃了我們一一一大罐那個狗糧啊
They've eaten us a whole, whole, whole can of dog food.
# 小黃 是不是小黃狗 嗯
Brownie! Are you a brown puppy? Hum?
# 哎 你們就進去
Ay! Can't you just go inside?
# 到這裡元多好玩啊 是不是
It's so much fun here, isn't it?
# 還有一條 過來
One more. Come here!
# 過來 小狗
Come here, puppy!
# 不過來
It's not coming.
# 不管它
Leave it alone.
# 今天晚上沒地方睡
It will have nowhere to sleep tonight.
# 它們就在這裡
So they're all here.
# 哎喲 那麼利 那麼利的牙齒
Ayo! What a sharp, sharp teeth!
# 你哎我
You bite me!
# 通通在這裡去
You all stay here!
# 嗯 啊 這個窩多晍和啊
Um! Ah! The kennel is so warm.
# 好啦 今天的視頻就到這(裡)[SIC]啦
Alright! The video ends here.